

Manish Chhetia

Technical Consultant

() +91-79099-86459

https://www.linkedin.com/in/manish-chhetia-6b322216/

Chhetia.manish@gmail.com

Indore, M.P., INDIA

About Me

A passionate technical personnel having over 12 years of experience in Information technology; looking for opportunities in esteemed organization.

Technical Skill(s)

- Architecture: Microservices, SOA, MVC etc
- .Net Core, .Net WebApplications, C#, VB.Net, VB 6.0
- RDBMS: SQL Server, Postgres, MongoDB
- C, C++
- Project Management : Jira, OpenProject, MS Project, Unfuddle
- DevOps: Jenkins, Docker
- TeamFoundationServer
- Operating Systems: Windows (XP, 7, 10, 11),
 Ubuntu
- MS Office (Word, Excel, Powerpoint)
- Design Patterns
- Solid Principles

Educational Background

Master of Science (Computer Science)

School of Computer Science and Electronics (Formerly Known as Institute of Computer Science and Electronics), Devi Ahilya Vishwavidyalaya, Indore Completed in May 1999 securing 73.20% CGPA 7.31

Bachelor of Science (Statistics)

Holkar Science College, Devi Ahilya Vishwavidyalaya, Indore Completed in April 1997 securing 72.39%

Publication

CoWriter of a book on Programming Language C - B.Sc. I Year Computer Science - Unified Course

Professional Experience

RWS

Technical Consultant

Mar 2023 - Oct 2023

Key responsibilities:

- Development (.Net Core, C#, SQL Server, MongoDB, AWS, Azure etc)
- Verification
- Deployment
- Monitoring
- Recruitment

SYSTANGO

Senior Project Manager

Jan 2021 - May 2021

Key responsibilities:

- Development (.Net Core, C#, SQL Server, AWS, PostGres etc)
- Verification
- Deployment
- Monitoring

Capgemini Technology Services India Limited

Manager

12thApr 2018 - 28th Jun 2019

01stDec 2011 - 31st Mar 2017

Key responsibilities:

- · Requirement Analysis (Statement of Work),
- Development (.Net Core, C#, SQL Server, AWS, Azure etc)
- Verification
- Deployment
- Monitoring
- Recruitment

Ideavate Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

Technical Lead

27th Jan 2009 - 18th Nov 2011

Key responsibilities:

- Analysis
- Development (.Net, C#, ASP.Net, Windows Mobile, SQL Server etc)
- Verification
- Deployment
- Recruitment

BatchMaster

Software Engineer

25th Feb 2005 - 29th Jan 2007

Key responsibilities:

- Development (VB.Net, VB 6.0, SQL Server)
- Verification

LinkedIn

- Received a number of recommendations from client(s), manager(s), colleague(s).
- Cleared skills test for: Object-Oriented Programming (OOP), REST APIs, C#, Microsoft Azure, Amazon Web Services (AWS), .Net, Agile Methodologies

Major Software Development Projects

1. InDesign Server (Translation Project)

The .Net Core web addon interacts with another web application called LanguageCloud and InDesign server for accepting the Adobe based IDML file formats and export them to PDF format using InDesign server features. InDesign server is hosted as soap service.

Tools: .Net Core, C#, InDesign Server, MongoDB, Azure, Git etc.

Responsibility: Research, Analysis, Development, Testing, Deployment, CI/CD.

2. Migration of Online Billing from Type - 1 to Type - 3

The product is based on online payments of customers for energy and utility bills using web and interactive voice response based interface. End Users can pay bills via web or calling to a designated number. Task assigned and accomplished was enabling payments via Interactive Voice Response (IVR) technology. Payments now are fully automated with ease of use; taking care of the secure details of the user via Cards (debit, credit) or Electronic Checks.

Tools: .Net, C#, ASP.Net, SQL Server, Interactive Voice Response, Voice Objects (Genesys Platform), Eclipse for Voice Objects, TeamFoundationServer.

Role: Senior Consultant, Manager.

Responsibilities: Analysis, Development, Testing, Deployment of services on IVR Platform, Project Monitoring.

3. WalshIntegrated (www.walshintegrated.com)

The web and mobile applications were targeting Healthcare domain; taking care of environmental friendliness information maintained in Hospitals (/other medical institutions). It provides a complete paper less automated records of equipment etc. I initiated working on the windows mobile application as a technical lead by guiding the associates on various areas and ended with a complete project management of applications (including requirement analysis, creation of project plan, delegating tasks for development & testing, release management, monitoring, client retention).

Tools: C# (Compact Edition), Windows Mobile 6.0, 6.1, 6.5 based client, (with SQL Compact Edition DB), PHP (on Server End), SQL Server 2005 (Database on Server), Android SDK 2.0 based client (with SQL Lite DB)

Role: Project Manager, Windows Mobile Developer.

Responsibilities: Requirement Analysis (Statement of Work), Estimation, Planning, Testing, Release Management, Project Monitoring, Client Retention.

4. UNIGO (www.unigo.com)

Social networking site facilitating complete information of various colleges, universities based out of US. The site supported a good level of Content management uploaded and managed by students and site editors. I have worked as a technical lead on the web portal, learnt EKTRON (CMS) and shared my knowledge with other team mates.

Tools: VS 2008, C#, ASP.Net, IIS, SQL Server 2008.

Role: Technical Lead.

Responsibilities: Development, Testing, Change Management using Unfuddle tool.

5. Set Top Box Application

Creating user interface for the Set Top Box hardware, providing state of art interface, ease of use, quick navigation, and extensive search based on a number of filter options. Modules assigned were to create optimized interface for searching and removing the flickering of screens. Tools: C#, (VS 2005), C++, IIS, Sony Digital Set Top Box Hardware Programming.

Role: Software Engineer

Responsibilities: Development, Testing.

6. Batch Master Enterprise® (Enterprise Resource Planning)

Batch Master is a process manufacturing software product available for complex chemical and other manufacturing industries. The product is integrated into SAP-B1, Microsoft Great Plains Dynamics, ACCPAC, MAS 90, Quick Books, Solomon and Tata-Ex. I have worked as a developer responsible for implementing sales and purchase modules, interfacing product with TataEx and have created setups.

Tools: VB.Net, VB 6.0, SQL Server, Crystal Reports, Installshield.

Role: Software Engineer

Responsibilities: Development, Testing.